<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mu-An Chiou - @muanchiou || @muan</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://muan.co</link>
    <atom:link href="http://muan.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Random Swiss</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Arrived at Zurich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tram door closed on me, hitting on my tibia, hurt so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got off the tram, was waiting to cross the street.&lt;br /&gt;
Some random Swiss said: just cross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After crossing, I tried to figure out which direction is the street I am looking for.&lt;br /&gt;
That random Swiss has walked off for about 30 meters.&lt;br /&gt;
Swiss looked back, paused, and walked back, asking &amp;ldquo;Are you looking for something?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pointed at the Google Maps, not knowing how to pronounce it.&lt;br /&gt;
Swiss pointed at places, and said &amp;ldquo;I am walking that way as well&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within a couple steps, I got tripped by a plank on the road and fell.&lt;br /&gt;
Scratch my thumb, it bled a bit. My iPhone screen was shuttered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Random Swiss asked me &amp;ldquo;Are you alright?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
I said &amp;ldquo;Yes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
Random Swiss asked again.&lt;br /&gt;
I said &amp;ldquo;Yes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
Random Swiss asked &amp;ldquo;Are you sure?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
I said &amp;ldquo;Well there&amp;rsquo;s nothing else I can do now.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We chatted. &lt;br /&gt;
Then we found the road. Swiss asked me for the apartment number and walked me to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swiss had been to Taipei for work before.&lt;br /&gt;
Swiss sounded like some sort of mechnical engineer.&lt;br /&gt;
Swiss said he then spent a week traveling the island, and like Taitung the most.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked about how Taiwanese people are all so nice.&lt;br /&gt;
People who live in the southern part of the island especially.&lt;br /&gt;
They don&amp;rsquo;t speak a word in English, but they want to help you SO MUCH as if it&amp;rsquo;s their lives' mission.&lt;br /&gt;
And you just smile and nod.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we found my place, the 24th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goodbye.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 02:43:50 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://muan.co/2013/08/29/random-swiss/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://muan.co/2013/08/29/random-swiss/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GitHub Hiring Story</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of us have heard how incredibly relaxed GitHub&amp;rsquo;s culture is, but not many people have actually experienced it first hand to be able to confirm it. After going through GitHub&amp;rsquo;s hiring process, I have to say it was honestly the best experience I have ever had. &lt;span class=&quot;muted&quot;&gt;Though bear in mind that I am still early in my years.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog/1269-the-github-hiring-experience&quot;&gt;The GitHub hiring experience&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cobyism&quot;&gt;Coby&lt;/a&gt; certainly helped me a lot in understanding GitHub&amp;rsquo;s process while I was in it. GitHub is so out of the ordinary that you do need to study up in order to get a grasp on where you are at. And here&amp;rsquo;s my take on everything. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/13072200.png&quot; alt=&quot;London Drinkup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;First Contact&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 months ago, I was taking my time in finding something new, while finishing off lots of personal projects. I talked to a bunch of companies during the time; it took some people a long time to say no, and for some it cost me a long time to find out it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a good fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of people talk about how interview should be a two-way process, but there is a problem: most interviews are not set up to be a two-way process. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be about people meeting people, but purely about the company screening you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I initially got in contact at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog/1471-london-drinkup&quot;&gt;GitHub London drinkup&lt;/a&gt; after &lt;a href=&quot;http://devslovebacon.com/&quot;&gt;BACON&lt;/a&gt;. I have almost never been to these kind of social events, because I am genuinely afraid of &lt;strong&gt;strangers in bulk&lt;/strong&gt;. I somehow got the courage that day, most likely because it was my birthday, and I went alone!!! I met Julie (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nrrrdcore&quot;&gt;@nrrrdcore&lt;/a&gt;) and Zach (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/holman&quot;&gt;@holman&lt;/a&gt;). &amp;hearts;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked about various things for a good chunk of time. Having saw both of their talks before, and being a female designer/developer like Julie, there were lots of questions I wanted to ask, things about how designer should code, how all web designers code in GitHub, what are passion projects like, what the bigger vision is and so on, I even told them that drinkups frighten me. It was a really nice, casual chat, they were both super friendly and easy to talk to, &lt;strong&gt;and I really can&amp;rsquo;t stress this enough.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the night, I mentioned my interest in GitHub to Julie, she asked me to drop her an email so we can talk more. I really didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be abrupt, but I thought it was appropriate at the time; she reminded me to send that email again right before I took off. &amp;hearts; How nice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon after, we started emailing back and forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Interviewing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiring takes time, and it&amp;rsquo;s time from both ends. In the first one and a half month I had some emails/Skype/FaceTime calls with a bunch of GitHubbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn&amp;rsquo;t moving fast, from time to time I waited for more than a week to get a response or to schedule a call time. I&amp;rsquo;ll be lying if I say I wasn&amp;rsquo;t bothered by that, but it was really pleasant nonetheless, here&amp;rsquo;s why: when people replied me late, they told me they were going to be late, and why they were. They make the effort to drop me a short email only to make sure I know what is going on. (Thank you especially &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/tclem&quot;&gt;@tclem&lt;/a&gt; ♥)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different from the usual interview setup, people I talked to made the purpose of the calls very clear to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We want to get to know you, and we want you to know us, so you can be sure you would like to work with us personally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my developer friends love GitHub, and almost everyone would like to work in GitHub simply because &lt;strong&gt;it is GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;. But through talking to real people working in GitHub, there comes a point when I felt &lt;strong&gt;I really want to work with these people!&lt;/strong&gt; It was perfectly possible that during the process I might realise that they are pricks and stop being interested in them, but it was the complete opposite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the calls were super casual, we talk about personal experiences, my usual design process, preprocessors I love and hate, joked about how me loving HAML (just for not having to close tags) is plain lazy. :P I was super nervous, but it was great fun at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of companies talk to you about what frameworks you use/they use, what would you choose out of Backbone, Angular and Ember, what is the most difficult technical puzzle you&amp;rsquo;ve solved recently and even ask you where would you want to be in 5 years, or who do you follow on Twitter. (Yes, I have been asked.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHubbers talked with me like real people, like friends. They asked &amp;ldquo;human&amp;rdquo; and sensible questions that you might ask a new friend during a coffee or a pint. They were so friendly that you would think it is silly to feel any pressure, although like me, you might still do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/13072201.png&quot; alt=&quot;Flight&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Onsite Interview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a bunch of skype/FaceTime calls, they invited me to fly over from London to San Francisco for an onsite interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the time we’re flying someone out, we mean business.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;small&gt;The GitHub Hiring Experience - Coby&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They offered to fly me in for extra days prior/following just to relax and adjust to jet lag before the interview, which was super nice. They booked me airport pickup services with a limo. I am not some hotshot like many of you, it was the first time I have people holding my name sign at the gate. After I checked in at the hotel, they got in touch to see if I am doing OK and if I need anything. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/WassupBryant&quot;&gt;Emma&lt;/a&gt; ♥)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few days of relaxing and meeting friends, here comes the first part of the onsite interview: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nrrrdcore&quot;&gt;@nrrrdcore&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jakeboxer&quot;&gt;@jakeboxer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mdo&quot;&gt;@mdo&lt;/a&gt; took me out for dinner. It was just a casual welcome dinner, and by casual, I mean CASUAL casual, as in they were talking about love for Chicken Nuggets, and how tiny humans make their apartment seem big. :) I was nervous and shy so didn&amp;rsquo;t talk much, but they were so funny and you can see that they get along really well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up was the interview day, I had breakfast with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tclem&quot;&gt;@tclem&lt;/a&gt;, whom I have already talked to online so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too nervous, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog/1519-jesse-toth-is-a-githubber&quot;&gt;badass&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jesseplusplus&quot;&gt;@jesseplusplus&lt;/a&gt;. They walked me to the office afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/13072202.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the day, I talked to about some 10 people, 2 at a time. It was super laid-back, just chatting. There was one thing surprised me the most &amp;ndash; everyone already knows a lot about me. They know about my recent projects, things I have built and shipped(not just the ones on my resume), they know how I got in touch, they know I am from Taiwan but I live in London and so on. It is surprising how rare this is the case, and this tells me that they took the time to get to know me, not just by looking at my resume, but actually took the time to read through stuff I have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked to developers, designers and also to my surprise &amp;ndash; the finance team! Normally when interviewing at a company, I will expect seeing developers, project managers or so, not people from a whole different department, but this was brilliant! People were not hard-divided into certain groups simply because they were non-techs working in a tech company or something. I enjoyed very much talking to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hotbootymasala&quot;&gt;@hotbootymasala&lt;/a&gt;, who used to live in London like me, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TaxAly&quot;&gt;@TaxAly&lt;/a&gt;, who codes quite a lot now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day finished at 3pm, which was rather early. At the end of it, I had a design session with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nrrrdcore&quot;&gt;@nrrrdcore&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mdo&quot;&gt;@mdo&lt;/a&gt;, it was unexpectedly not as intimidating as I imagined, &lt;a href=&quot;http://instagram.com/p/ag-UenJanP/&quot;&gt;@nrrrdcore drew a Clippy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was the first and the only &amp;lsquo;technical&amp;rsquo; interview I had with GitHub, so I asked: &amp;ldquo;How are you guys sure about my coding ability?&amp;rdquo; and well, they told me that obviously they have read through my GitHub profile, and they meant it. Just on top of his head, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mdo&quot;&gt;@mdo&lt;/a&gt; listed almost all of my project repositories and told me how each one showed them what I can do. Wow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/13072203.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucky for me, in the evening one of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://passion-projects.github.com/&quot;&gt;passion projects&lt;/a&gt; was being held, so I hang out more that night to check it out, chatted with some more people, met &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bleikamp&quot;&gt;@bleikamp&lt;/a&gt;. And that was the end of the onsite interview.., almost!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A little incident&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day after, I received an email from someone I met briefly but didn&amp;rsquo;t get a chance to talk to on the interview day. He introduced himself and said if I have got any more questions about GitHub he&amp;rsquo;ll be happy to answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be because the interview was over, I had the illusion that I can now begin to ask a bunch of silly questions and not get judged by, so I replied asking if he&amp;rsquo;ll be able to meet and have a chat, and he said yes right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/mtodd&quot;&gt;@mtodd&lt;/a&gt; ended up spending a whole Saturday afternoon with me in the GitHub office, just answering my endless questions about GitHub and chatting with me about basically everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/13072204.png&quot; alt=&quot;Octocat pillow&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was really glad to have the chance spending time with him that afternoon, I got to know so much more about GitHub. I had a peek of the weekend office, sat in an egg chair hugging an octocat pillow, and hung out in the guitar room. Without the pressure of it being an interview (although it definitely still counted), I was a whole lot more relaxed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I flew back to London a day later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;At the end of everything&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the whole process, I did not talk to any &amp;ldquo;HR people.&amp;rdquo; I met and talked to people who actually work in GitHub doing the same thing as what I will be doing, and people who will be working with me if I got hired. There was really an impressive amount of engineering time set aside purely for hiring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching from the outside, I saw GitHub being this great company that builds a much loved product, and I thought they must have everything all figured out; but I came to realise, &lt;strong&gt;they do not have everything figured out&lt;/strong&gt;, and it is so awesome. &amp;hearts;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub is the people, and obviously people make mistakes, no one is ever perfect, and they are not afraid to show it. They recognise their weaknesses and try to better everything all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the interview I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but feeling out of place, simply because GitHub is GitHub; but after the whole interview process, GitHub is no longer the entity I used to think it was. GitHub is that group of people I met with; they are approachable, friendly, and no different to you and I.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My concern as a candidate was to make sure I will love my job, I will get excited at what I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing, I will like the company and most importantly, enjoy working with the people. And from what I have learned from the process, the people and the culture, I find everything at GitHub extremely appealing to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started writing this blog post before they flew me to San Francisco, and I finished the post on the plane back to London. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know if I was going to get an offer while writing this initially, it almost felt like a stupid teenage crush; fortunately for me, turns out in the end our love was mutual ♥, I got an offer a couple days after I got back to London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously not having actually worked in GitHub yet, there could be a possibility that everyone is secretly annoying, @mtodd lied about how TPW really is, and I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t see all these things from the outside. Although I highly doubt these, I do only speak for what I&amp;rsquo;ve already known. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/muan-fast.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Spinning, I am spinning!&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week is my first week at GitHub, good luck to me. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://octodex.github.com/&quot;&gt;May the octocats be with you&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;hearts;&lt;br /&gt;
Have you heard that &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/about/jobs&quot;&gt;we are currently hiring&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. Thank you &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nrrrdcore&quot;&gt;Julie&lt;/a&gt; for everything. You are so awesome. &amp;hearts; &amp;hearts; &amp;hearts; &amp;hearts; &amp;hearts;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 23:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://muan.co/2013/07/24/github-hiring-story/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://muan.co/2013/07/24/github-hiring-story/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Git wedding-speech</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of my friends just got married/got engaged recently. People plan their weddings in all different ways. I suddenly wondered if any couple has ever planned a wedding in a GitHub repository, so I typed &amp;ldquo;wedding&amp;rdquo; into &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog/1381-a-whole-new-code-search&quot;&gt;GitHub search box&lt;/a&gt;. And found this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;お互いの人生という repository に、それぞれの人生の branch が、ここにmergeされました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ときにはconflictが発生することもあるでしょう。そんなときは慌てずきちんとソースを読んでconflictを解消することが重要です。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;夫はgit blameしてはいけません。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;妻からpull requestがあったら、すみやかにmergeしてください。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;何か困ったことや問題が発生したらうやむやにせずIssueを登録して、きちんと対応していきましょう。長い人生を一緒に歩んでいくうえで大切なことです。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;人生設計として milestone を意識するのも良いと思います。いつまでにこうしよう、何歳になったらこうなっているといいね、という意識を共有することで人生がより豊かになります。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;周りの夫婦を見て、これはいいなと思うところは、積極的にcherry-pickしていきましょう。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chris4403/wedding-party-speech&quot;&gt;https://github.com/chris4403/wedding-party-speech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know Japanese, but I know the fragmented Kanji(漢字), and it looks so sweet with all the Git/GitHub terms, so I asked my Japanese-fluent sister to translate it. It turned out to be so extremely sweet, especially for a female geek like me, I can only wish I was there to see the bride&amp;rsquo;s reaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s my sister&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/muan/wedding-party-speech/blob/master/speech-zh-tw.md&quot;&gt;Traditional Chinese translation&lt;/a&gt;, and an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/muan/wedding-party-speech/blob/master/speech-en.md&quot;&gt;English translation&lt;/a&gt; by myself. The English translation I feel lack of the original cuteness and the jokingly-warning impressions, which was a shame; so, pull requests please. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hearts;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 05:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://muan.co/2013/07/21/git-weddnig-speech/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://muan.co/2013/07/21/git-weddnig-speech/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Facebook Filter</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I use Facebook a lot. A friend of mine doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite get it, he said: &amp;ldquo;who cares about where &lt;em&gt;someone&lt;/em&gt; went or what &lt;em&gt;someone&lt;/em&gt; ate last weekend?&amp;rdquo; But after putting himself in my shoes, I think he got it, at least a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being away from home in a foreign country, with most of my close friends back in Taiwan, Facebook is awesome for keeping up with how my friends are doing; especially nowadays some people think it is OK to send wedding invitations through Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Facebook can be utterly annoying sometimes, your home stream can really easily be taken over by a stupid trend. Like after Miami Heat won, I, as someone who supported the Spurs, really don&amp;rsquo;t need to see Heat&amp;rsquo;s fans glow!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was sure that there must be something out there, a Chrome extension that does exactly this. After a bit of search I found one that comes with 20 other features I don&amp;rsquo;t need, so I was actually not that motivated to install it, or write one for myself for that matter. I just put up with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then a friend of mine started saying how he wanted to hide anything to do with NBA/ Miami Heat as well, I thought, building this for someone else to use is a lot more fun than building it for myself! So I replied saying: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m gonna build it!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Screenshot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/13063001.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/filter/ongmpdiioadbiooegapnhbfglmaacpcd&quot; class=&quot;big-button green&quot;&gt;Facebook filter in Chrome Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/muan/filter&quot; class=&quot;big-button red&quot;&gt;Facebook filter on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built it over lunch and sent the link straight to my friend. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[x] Something to build&lt;br/ &gt;
[x] Someone to use it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;♥&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope next time it&amp;rsquo;d be something more practical. 乁( ◔ ౪◔)「&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 17:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://muan.co/2013/06/29/facebook-filter/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://muan.co/2013/06/29/facebook-filter/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Landing Page for Kickstarter Projects</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of my friends have been working on &lt;a href=&quot;http://stair-rover.com&quot;&gt;Stair-Rover&lt;/a&gt;, and they launched &lt;a href=&quot;http://kck.st/12bbLkw&quot;&gt;their Kickstarter project&lt;/a&gt; today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/iK5dZiGgm5s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They asked me yesterday about how to make a landing page with some sharing buttons, and showed me the references they found about how to make a project landing page, and how it would help encouraging people to share, and help tracking actions better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason why they came to me was that they tried to follow the tips &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fourhourworkweek.com/blog/2012/12/18/hacking-kickstarter-how-to-raise-100000-in-10-days-includes-successful-templates-e-mails-etc/&quot;&gt;Soma shared, about hacking kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;, specifically &lt;strong&gt;Step 7&lt;/strong&gt;. They ended up landing on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/somawater/kickstarter&quot;&gt;Soma&amp;rsquo;s GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; and had no idea how to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be really daunting for people who are completely unfamiliar with programming to deal with domains, hostings and code. But nowadays there are so many tools making our lives as developers easier day by day, we should really try to make them accessible to people outside of the tech circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I put together &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/muan/kickstarter&quot;&gt;a Kickstarter landing page template&lt;/a&gt; based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.somawater.co/ksshare/&quot;&gt;Soma&amp;rsquo;s landing page&lt;/a&gt;, and here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://muan.co/kickstarter&quot;&gt;a demo&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to make sure &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/muan/kickstarter#instruction&quot;&gt;the instruction&lt;/a&gt; is dead easy so people with no programming knowledge are able to set up a landing page for their projects and host it on GitHub within minutes. And it does exactly that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Jekyll and GitHub pages, I was able to achieve the goal, and let people set up everything within 4 steps! Using Jekyll allows people to change configuration in a YAML file, without having to dig around HTML files and get confused over a missing tag. Hosting on GitHub pages is so easy that people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even notice the magic floating around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/muan/kickstarter#instruction&quot; class=&quot;big-button blue&quot;&gt;Read instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://muan.co/kickstarter&quot; class=&quot;big-button green&quot;&gt;See demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After pushing the repo to GitHub last night, I sent a link to the instruction to my friend, and he set it up within minutes without my help, making me very happy. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 12:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://muan.co/2013/06/19/kickstarter-landing-page/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://muan.co/2013/06/19/kickstarter-landing-page/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>1 Million Pageviews</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zeczec.com/&quot;&gt;Zeczec&lt;/a&gt; (my not-really-a-startup startup) and designer Han Lee had &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.haniboi.com&quot;&gt;a little collaboration project.&lt;/a&gt; It started simple and small. Han is a friend of us and he had previously launched &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zeczec.com/projects/haniboi&quot;&gt;a successful project&lt;/a&gt; on zeczec. (we&amp;rsquo;re a crowdfunding platform)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 months ago, Han had this new idea with little people holding word signs, and at the time &amp;ldquo;no nukes&amp;rdquo; was a really big topic in Taiwan, people were asking him to make pictures like this for their facebook covers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fbcdn-sphotos-c-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/482718_532796233439201_775890733_n.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not long after his 500th manually made people-holding-signs image, He contacted us for the idea of making an image generator, and immediately I said yes. I think for the most part it is that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really used Canvas before, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find an excuse to use it, and this was perfect! Therefore, just like me facing any other exciting new projects, I dived right in and finished most of the code within couple of days. We decided to call it UPUP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a bigger plan, Han wants to make lots of products around this concept, toys, stickers, notebooks&amp;hellip;. He planned to put it on zeczec to raise funding for them, so we agreed to put UPUP on hold until he&amp;rsquo;s ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn&amp;rsquo;t make the generator public, and at the same time we didn&amp;rsquo;t really think it&amp;rsquo;s going to be anything even if we did. So we tested the generator publicly, I put it on GitHub, we test uploading to facebook and so on. No one cares about letting it get out, as it is so unlikely that it will blow up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time passed by, it was getting closer and closer to the date we planned to launch the project. We tested UPUP a few more times, and just like before, we didn&amp;rsquo;t bother to hide it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/943420_513806072018857_1221631741_n.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 29 May, it got out, all of a sudden. Initially we noticed images being shared by a couple of friends but didn&amp;rsquo;t think much of it, but suddenly it became 30 friends, then before we knew it, the generator is shared by the most popular local tech blog. We got 50,000 views in 5 hours, and the number of active users on site was soaring, going from 400 to 1800+.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were not prepared at all, and we decided to shut it down(which was a questionable decision), and take some time to come up with a strategy. I was dead worried, thinking after we shut it down we might not be able to get it this popular again, it was just about to take off at the time&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To most of our surprises, as soon as we took down the site with a notice saying: &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ll be back.&amp;rdquo; (and etc,) the number of our facebook fans started soaring. While the site was up, we were gaining about 30 likes per hour, then after we took it down, it was 300 likes per hour!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we decided to put it back on again on the 31 May for fear that people might lose interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/zeczec.com&quot;&gt;zeczec&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s gained more than 30,000 facebook fans, UPUP has reached &lt;strong&gt;1,200,000 pageviews&lt;/strong&gt;, been on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zg5F3v-PVD0&amp;amp;list=PLB_xus-d9BFus7wOV5OKopUy79zI3An37&quot;&gt;4 television news programs&lt;/a&gt;, numerous online medias, &lt;a href=&quot;http://epaper.skypost.hk/fileData/ePapers/20130603/1088240486/index.html#/12/zoomed&quot;&gt;metro newspaper in HongKong&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=516265595095796&quot;&gt;shared&lt;/a&gt; by the lead signer of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mayday_(Taiwanese_band)&quot;&gt;Mayday&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10151594249563926&quot;&gt;Gal Gadot&lt;/a&gt; of Fast and Furious, and more&amp;hellip; all within 7 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/upup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still don&amp;rsquo;t know what exactly happened, and we&amp;rsquo;ve experienced the privilege and pain of being popular by being trolled heavily and said mean things to, and it hurts! These internet people are mean, do they know they&amp;rsquo;re criticising a human being?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of friends in Taiwan are congratulating us for this seemingly extremely successful campaign. We still don&amp;rsquo;t have Han&amp;rsquo;s big-picture project up on zeczec, and the hype is indeed likely to die down soon, but we had a great run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s our first million, lots of things went wrong, lots of things didn&amp;rsquo;t go as planned and lots of opportunities were missed. It&amp;rsquo;d be nice if we were more prepared, but who&amp;rsquo;d know what would have happen if so? :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, you can &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.haniboi.com&quot;&gt;play it here&lt;/a&gt;, this weekend we&amp;rsquo;re dedicating the site to newly grads hence the dresses. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 06:46:17 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://muan.co/2013/06/07/zeczec-haniboi-upup/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://muan.co/2013/06/07/zeczec-haniboi-upup/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Twitter Followers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have many Twitter followers so it is an easy number to remember, I never intended to remember it, but it was just in my face so it is hard not to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed how it drops sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHY? GOD, WHY? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it happens one too many times, I hid it with CSS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/muan/4de4b806c4db59285beb.js?file=twitter-followers.css&quot;&gt; &lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;ll be all. As you were.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 20:53:25 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://muan.co/2013/05/24/twitter-followers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://muan.co/2013/05/24/twitter-followers/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Noise</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I live next to a huge mall in London. Last night as I was walking through the mall to the grocery store on the other side, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but noticed the terrible music that was blasting through the speakers and into my ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally I put on my headphones to stop what was happening, but seconds later, I realised it was not just the music. There were millions of other things being shoved into my eyes &amp;ndash; the display windows, the colourful stands, the flashing digital signages, the wallpapers, they are all trying to talk to me, all trying to sell me something. I lowered my head only to find there were advertising stickers on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year I went back to Taiwan for a couple of weeks. While I was there I kept feeling there were this constant noise that I cannot get rid of. I cannot have one single quiet moment and it annoyed me so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, I am from Taipei, and this is just an ordinary street:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/13052101.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Taipei&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is mad. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly though, I have never noticed it while I was living there, it was only after 5 years living in the UK that I realised there is this massive difference. London is in comparison a lot quieter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine every signage has a voice, and as soon as you lay eyes on it, it starts talking: &amp;ldquo;Hey are you hungry? We serve a mean pork belly bun!&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Do you need a haircut? We are offering student discount! Not that you look like a student.&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;We sell rice burger and we are from Japan! Why not come in?&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Wanna buy a lottery? Chance to win 5 million!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Would you please shut up? I just want to go home!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I missed London a lot while I was there, I missed the quietness; regardless growing up in the city, I have never &amp;ldquo;liked&amp;rdquo; quietness  particularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So being in the mall reminded me, the other day when I was at the gym, there was something similar. The TVs, all 8 of them, right in front of the treadmills. Are you kidding me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything in this mad world now requires us to make a deliberate effort to shut things off, otherwise they will sneak through every possible crack to get into your head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To block the noise, it might be as easy as putting on your headphones, but it might not be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taiwanese are particularly good at, I mean, addicted to, shoving things into your face. Take Yahoo! Taiwan for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/13052102.png&quot; alt=&quot;Yahoo Taiwan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the second largest web portal in Taiwan:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/13052104.png&quot; alt=&quot;PCHome&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is as if leaving white space is a deadly sin.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not showing them so I can bash Taiwanese websites, I am showing them as examples of the extreme cases, and it is bad, so we need to move towards the opposite direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, we often see nice, clean, well-spaced websites when we work in tech, but &lt;strong&gt;this is not about the design&lt;/strong&gt;, this is about the amount of information you present. We all know how scrolling works, but is it necessary to give people 20000 pixels to scroll?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not good at selling at all, so I am not talking about what will work for a business. I am talking about NOT shoving things to people&amp;rsquo;s faces when they don&amp;rsquo;t need the information. Why? Because there needs to be a noise control and I want my quietness, so should you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If people click through to an article they do not need to know who you are, where you&amp;rsquo;re from and who do you work for before they read the article, and obviously they would not want to subscribe to your blog out of nowhere. Sure, less clicks means higher conversion rate, but it comes with a price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simplicity is not hard, you just have to leave certain unimportant things out. Just be aware of the Signal v.s. Noise ratio. Things that are not the signal, are noise. You might as well have the most bullet-proof rationale as to why everything just NEEDS to be shown and above the fold, but just listen to your page. How many of the things are shouting? How come you are not deaf yet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our environment is gradually upping the volume for what seems to be a perfectly legitimate reason &amp;ndash; sales. And we are getting used to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be a day, when we realised that the background noise is dominating our world, and it is going to be too late, as we can no longer hear the signal from all the noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A somewhat relevant video:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/N5WurXNec7E&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 04:02:39 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://muan.co/2013/05/21/noise/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://muan.co/2013/05/21/noise/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scribble, a Jekyll Theme</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: 25 Sep 2012&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided it was too much work to add a new theme, and rather not destroy the joy of redesigning blogs by constraining myself with frameworks, so.. from now on the themes will be in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/muan/muan.github.com&quot;&gt;the repository of this blog&lt;/a&gt;, meaning if you do want to use it, it&amp;rsquo;s going to take you some setup time, migrating posts or however you do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing remains to be true: you&amp;rsquo;re all welcome to use the themes I made, edit it however you like, only that I will not be doing support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browse the design changes using this neat &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/muan/muan.github.com/releases&quot;&gt;release view&lt;/a&gt; of the repository. ♥&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: 20 May 2013&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am now working on &lt;strong&gt;Wardrobe&lt;/strong&gt;, which would be a jekyll setup with 3-5 themes to start with, it is currently work in progress but you can have &lt;a href=&quot;http://themes.muan.co/&quot;&gt;a sneak preview here&lt;/a&gt; (one of the themes.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/muanchiou&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/muan/jekyll-wardrobe&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; to keep yourself in the loop. ♥&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember &lt;a href=&quot;/2013/04/08/jekyll-themes/&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;? Yap, I have been busy, but it is no excuse. There is only one reason for why I didn&amp;rsquo;t start the project &amp;ndash; It is too big to start. I failed to find a way in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How exactly do you make it easy for people to switch themes without turning this project into some huge monster? I don&amp;rsquo;t know, and couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the time to think about it thoroughly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought about building the themes on top of &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllbootstrap.com&quot;&gt;jekyll bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;. Well, it would be sensible, but no, not at this point at least. It would be a huge barrier for me in terms of kicking start this project, because then I&amp;rsquo;d need to understand how things are structured in jekyll bootstrap&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I decided to keep it as simple as possible, just do basically what &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/holman/left&quot;&gt;Left&lt;/a&gt; (by &lt;a href=&quot;http://zachholman.com/posts/left/&quot;&gt;Zach Holman&lt;/a&gt;) does, and it, is, done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Scribble.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Scribble is the first theme, read more about it on &lt;a href=&quot;http://scribble.muan.co/2013/05/06/scribble-the-jekyll-theme/&quot;&gt;the demo site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;ll be all. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 21:38:50 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://muan.co/2013/05/05/scribble-the-jekyll-theme/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://muan.co/2013/05/05/scribble-the-jekyll-theme/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scribble</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been busy building &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zeczec.com&quot;&gt;zeczec&lt;/a&gt;. This version was shipped 2 weeks ago, and I guess I&amp;rsquo;d never really be happy with it. These are from the past 2 weeks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/13050501.png&quot; alt=&quot;github graph&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, so evidently upon shipping zeczec, I stopped writing blogs and stopped redesigning my blog(!), which is bad, but I just could not spare the time, too many bugs and too many improvements to make. :S&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking about finishing the &lt;a href=&quot;/2013/04/14/A-Story-1/&quot;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; for a long time, but having left it for too long, I cannot really find a place to start&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, instead of keeping finding out where and how to start, I thought I try to get back on track by redesigning my blog! :) And as expected, as soon as I open Sublime(not really, Sublime was never closed), the new design was born within 2 hours. So here it is, now the next thing would be to start writing again. Hope that would happen soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mean time,&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m craving some dumplings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 21:38:50 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://muan.co/2013/05/05/scribble/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://muan.co/2013/05/05/scribble/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>